<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Visual Studio - Tag - MAUI, c'est clair !</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/tags/visual-studio/</link><description>Visual Studio - Tag - MAUI, c'est clair !</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jeanemmanuel.baillat@gmail.com (Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT)</managingEditor><webMaster>jeanemmanuel.baillat@gmail.com (Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/tags/visual-studio/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Target multiple environments in .NET MAUI</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tips/multi-environments-project-configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tips/multi-environments-project-configuration/</guid><description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re developing mobile applications, software or websites, it&amp;rsquo;s common practice to set up multiple environments for a project. This makes it easy to test new features without risking the data of our users.
In this article, I will show you how a .NET MAUI application can target different environments through multiple project configurations.
‎ To simplify the reading of this article, we will only focus on iOS &amp;amp; Android. However, the process is similar for other platforms.</description></item><item><title>Create a .NET MAUI App without Shell</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tips/maui-app-with-no-shell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tips/maui-app-with-no-shell/</guid><description>Since the official release of .NET MAUI, it is not possible to create a new project where Visual Studio does not add a default Shell. Fortunately, there is a very simple way to get rid of it!
Shell or not Shell? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you! When creating a new app in .NET MAUI, Visual Studio does not offer many configuration options:
Of course, there is .NET MAUI Blazor, but it is a completely different framework.</description></item><item><title>Music player display - Media playback</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/8-music-player-display-media-playback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/8-music-player-display-media-playback/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we started setting up the music player controls. In the last chapter, we worked on setting up the first visual elements of the music player. Two components were discovered: the Label and the Slider.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to continue our good work and reproduce a whole series of buttons to control the media.
War of the Buttons To listen to music, our user needs key functions like: play a song, skip to the next track, etc.</description></item><item><title>First run of the app .NET MAUI</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/3-first-run-of-the-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/3-first-run-of-the-project/</guid><description><![CDATA[‎ To ease your read, please start from the project containing all the different steps applied so far in this tutorial. To do so, refer to the project setup guide and resume from the sample located in the folder &ldquo;0 - Get Started&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s now time to get the app running. We&rsquo;ll also take the opportunity to look at the source code 🙂
But for our application to work, we still have two points to address: the app initialization and above all, managing its execution state.]]></description></item><item><title>Setup the project .NET MAUI</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/2-setup-the-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/2-setup-the-project/</guid><description>Today we&amp;rsquo;ll start building our first application! Let’s first set up your working environment, and then you’ll have something concrete soon. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Which tools for development ? Let’s first see the tools you will need to develop your app.
‎ 🐒‎ ‎ By the way, do I need to be on Windows, MacOS or Linux? Actually, there is no particular pre-requisite to develop an app with .NET MAUI, unless you own a very old fashion computer and you never did update anything… 🤔 Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly a matter of preference!</description></item></channel></rss>