<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>My First App - Series - MAUI, c'est clair !</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/series/my-first-app/</link><description>My First App - Series - MAUI, c'est clair !</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jeanemmanuel.baillat@gmail.com (Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT)</managingEditor><webMaster>jeanemmanuel.baillat@gmail.com (Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/series/my-first-app/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create animations in .NET MAUI for a disco atmosphere</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/15-add-animations-to-an-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/15-add-animations-to-an-app/</guid><description>‎ This post is part of a series (”My First App”). To ease your read, please start from the project containing all the different steps applied so far in this tutorial. To do so, refer to the project setup guide and resume from the sample located in the folder “5 - Music Player”. Welcome to the final episode of this series! ✌️ If you&amp;rsquo;ve followed the series so far, then you should have an app you can use to listen to a few music tracks.</description></item><item><title>Listen to a playlist with MediaElement</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/14-skip-next-or-previous-with-mediaelement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:14 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/14-skip-next-or-previous-with-mediaelement/</guid><description><![CDATA[‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we have set up the MediaElement. Last time, we looked at how to download music directly from the app. But it&rsquo;s been the same music from the start!
Wouldn&rsquo;t the app be much nicer if you could listen to more songs? Well that’s ideal because today we&rsquo;re integrating a music playlist!
Playlist creation To do this, let&rsquo;s define the list of songs available in the application as follows:]]></description></item><item><title>Download an audio file in .NET MAUI</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/13-download-audio-file/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:13 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/13-download-audio-file/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we have set up the MediaElement. Here we go again for a new chapter!
It&amp;rsquo;s already episode 13 of this series, so I hope it&amp;rsquo;s still relatively easy to follow! But you may have questions or comments. If you do, ask me in the comments at the bottom of the article, or e-mail me directly (jeanemmanuel.baillat@gmail.com)!
Today, we will have a look at how to enable the user to download the music that is currently playing.</description></item><item><title>Control the volume with MediaElement</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/12-control-volume-with-mediaelement/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:12 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/12-control-volume-with-mediaelement/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we have set up the MediaElement. In the previous post, we saw how to move the playhead with our own Slider control. And I know it was a bit long! Hang on, we are not far from the end of this series 🙂
So today we are going to look at how to implement volume control, also with the help of a Slider.</description></item><item><title>Control the playback position with MediaElement</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/11-control-playback-position-with-mediaelement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:11 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/11-control-playback-position-with-mediaelement/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we have set up the MediaElement. In the previous article, we discovered the MediaElement for playing audio files, but with the help of our own controls. Remember the Sliders we set up? They&amp;rsquo;re cool, but they&amp;rsquo;re useless! 😄
So today, we are going to implement the playhead control, to allow the user to move to a specific frame in the track.</description></item><item><title>Play music in .NET MAUI with MediaElement</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/10-play-music-with-mediaelement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/10-play-music-with-mediaelement/</guid><description><![CDATA[‎ To ease your read, please start from the project containing all the different steps applied so far in this tutorial. To do so, refer to the project setup guide and resume from the sample located in the folder &ldquo;4 - All Media Controls&rdquo;. Before starting this new chapter, I wanted to congratulate you on all the progress you&rsquo;ve made!
Now that we&rsquo;re well advanced on the visual side, we can develop the core of the application and make it a little more functional.]]></description></item><item><title>Music player display - Volume</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/9-music-player-display-volume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:09 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/9-music-player-display-volume/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we started setting up the music player controls. In the last chapter, we worked on setting up the media playback controls. We discovered in particular a new type of button: the ImageButton component.
Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to further develop our user interface with the integration of volume controls. This is the final stretch before we start implementing the core of our music player, so hang on!</description></item><item><title>Music player display - Media playback</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/8-music-player-display-media-playback/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/8-music-player-display-media-playback/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please resume from this chapter where we started setting up the music player controls. In the last chapter, we worked on setting up the first visual elements of the music player. Two components were discovered: the Label and the Slider.
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to continue our good work and reproduce a whole series of buttons to control the media.
War of the Buttons To listen to music, our user needs key functions like: play a song, skip to the next track, etc.</description></item><item><title>Music player display - Time tracker</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/7-music-player-display-time-tracker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 00:00:07 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/7-music-player-display-time-tracker/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please start from the project containing all the different steps applied so far in this tutorial. To do so, refer to the project setup guide and resume from the sample located in the folder &amp;ldquo;3 - Page Scaffolding&amp;rdquo;. In the previous article, we set up a matrix to display all the controls of our music player. So we can now add concrete elements for the user!</description></item><item><title>Arrange elements on a .NET MAUI page</title><link>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/6-arrange-elements-on-a-page/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:06 +0000</pubDate><author>Jean-Emmanuel BAILLAT</author><guid>https://www.mauicestclair.fr/en/posts/tutos/my-first-app/6-arrange-elements-on-a-page/</guid><description>‎ To ease your read, please start from the project containing all the different steps applied so far in this tutorial. To do so, refer to the project setup guide and resume from the sample located in the folder named &amp;ldquo;2 - Navigation&amp;rdquo;. With this new chapter, we begin a series of articles focused on the visual aspect of the app, and there is a good chance that you will like it!</description></item></channel></rss>